# Mezu Orizu



duzioristo@gmail.com



+23409090202853



linkedin.com/in/mezu-orizu-a50612230



https://github.com/MZT7

### **Summary**

I am a fullstack developer with industry experience building websites and web applications. I specialize in php and have professional experience working with Laravel and Livewire. I also have experience developing a wide range of web applications for start-up and small to enterprise level web applications.

Core skills and strengths:

\_\_\_\_\_

- ✓ WAMP (Windows, Apache, MySQL, PHP5)
- ✓ Laragon
- ✓ Frameworks like Laravel, React.js
- √ eCommerce: Laravel Ecommerce
- ✓ JavaScript, jQuery, Alpinejs
- ✓ Databases design, programming and optimization
- ✓ PHP7, MySQL5, HTML5, Laravel Livewire and UI integration
- ✓ Code versioning using Git
- ✓ Payment gateway integration (Paystack , Stripe, PayPal)
- ✓ Mailing API (Sendpulse, Sendinblue)
- ✓ REST API development and integration

Please contact me to discuss your requirements to determine how I can utilize my skills to help you...

# **Experience**



### Fullstack developer

Oristouniversal

Apr 2021 - Present (1 year 3 months +)

I was tasked to create a web app to advertise the companies chemical products and connect them with their customers using Sendinblue email service and Whatsapp API in contact form and page respectively. As the only developer involved in the project.

- I built the web application using Laravel blade, Laravel, Tailwindcss and Alpinejs.
- I hosted the web application using shared hosting and was in charge of managing ssh interactions.

# -

### **Web Developer**

Opiofiber

Feb 2019 - Dec 2019 (11 months)

I created the website to help advertise the companies manufactured products.

- I created the website using html, css and jquery.
- I hosted the website on garantor using shared hosting services.

### Web Developer

Soughtoutroofing

Mar 2018 - Nov 2018 (9 months)

I created the website to help advertise the companies manufactured products.

- I created the website using html, css and jquery.
- I hosted the website on garantor using shared hosting services.

## **Education**



# Babcock University, Ilishan-Remo, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science 2014 - 2019

### **Skills**

Bootstrap • laravel blade • AlpineJs • Tailwind CSS • JavaScript • Laravel • Livewire • PHP • HTML • React.js